Mark Hario

Software Engineer

Full-stack JavaScript software engineer with an eye for UX, efficiency, and accessibility. Independent, organized and self-motivated, with experience designing and building dense, intuitive apps and the APIs to feed them. Known for being flexible, pragmatic, and respectful.

Experience

Denovo (Boulder, CO)

July 2019 - Current

Software Engineer – UI / UX

- Performed agile software development rebuilding legacy app on Vue.js.
- Designed and built 'user requests dashboard,' a GitLab abstraction; includes graphs built with Plotly and multiple animated interface elements.
- Improved legacy code while seamlessly integrating new features.
- Designed prototypes and developed new features and work flows.
- Assumed scrum mastery, team leadership, and product ownership.
- Trained and mentored junior team members.

IHS Markit (Boulder, CO)

May 2017 - June 2019

Associate Software Engineer II

- Provided development and deployment within a large, interdisciplinary team for a major financial client serving millions of page views daily.
- Overhauled the 'Detailed Quote' investing pages with new Vue.js apps featuring updated accessibility, functionality, and user experience.
- Collaborated with designers to ensure pixel-perfect consistency with designs, and offered improvements and feedback.
- Ensured features were accessible to screen readers, partially sighted, and physically disabled users.
- Performed maintenance and upgrades to legacy code, mostly C#.

Education

Remote Immersive Program

2016 - 2017

Full stack JavaScript Web Development

Fullstack Academy

Bachelor of Science Degree

2012 - 2014

Welding Engineering Technology

Ferris State University

Contact

hario.us

hario.mark@gmail.com

(734)755 - 2807

Louisville, CO

github.com/mhario

linkedin.com/in/mark-hario

Skills

Essential

Respect & Integrity

Communication

Teamwork

Technologies

Vue / Vuex

React / Redux

React Native

HTML5 / jQuery

CSS3 / Sass / Less

Design / UX

Accessibility

Git / GitLab / Jira

Node / Express

Mongo / Postgres

Mocha / Chai

Training

Docker

AWS

Dev Ops

Education, continued

Associate of Applied Science
Welding Technology
Monroe County Community College

2007 — *2010*

Projects

3D Game Of Life

- Conway's Game of Life, converted into 3D
- Rendered with three.js, interface built with React.
- Will soon be moving to the cloud and adding a database.

BiteSwipeLite

- A small app that offers a fun way to choose where to go for dinner.
- Originally built in React Native; rebuilding in React as a web app.

Previous Work Experience

Vizient Mfg Solutions (Bettendorf, IA) September 2014 — September 2016 *Robot Programmer*

- Programmed Fanuc arc welding robots for customers in the agriculture industry, utilizing non-contact laser sensing, multi-pass welding, and coordinated motion.
- Evaluated tooling designs using Fanuc WeldPRO simulations and cycle-time estimates; suggested improvements to engineering designs to improve welding automation efficiency.
- Trained new personnel in robot programming and wrote training documentation for Fanuc WeldPRO software.

Pridgeon & Clay (Grand Rapids, MI) August 2013 — December 2013 *Welding Engineering Intern*

> Production support and process improvements in an automotive manufacturing environment.